# Jonathan P. Healy

jonathan.p.healy@gmail.com | 858.395.4047

Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub

Full Stack Web Developer with a B.A. in Business Administration. Experienced in management within the service industry. Bold curiosity in learning new technologies and excited for the challenges that lay ahead. Strengths in HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Media Queries, APIs, MySql, JavaScript, JQuery, and NodeJS.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of California San Diego

Full Stack Web Development Program

2017

- An intensive 12-week program dedicated to designing and full stack web development
- Skills learned consisted of HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars JS, & React Js

University of California Riverside

B.S. Business Administration

2009

Accolades

- Brotherhood chairman of Kappa Alpha Order and member of Interfraternity Council
- Nicodemus Wilderness Project Award, issued for participation in environmental cleanup tasks on behalf of the University

### **APPLICATIONS BUILT**

Pick-A-Flick 2017

- A movie search application that allows you to search movies based on your current mood.
- Contributing backend developer in a team of six
- Responsible for MovieDB API calls and rendering of data in ReactJS
- https://github.com/frogman91/Foupon

Foupon 2017

- A restaurant web application that allows you to "like" or "dislike" nearby eateries and will in turn populate your profile with applicable coupons to your favorite spots!
- Contributing backend developer in a team of four
- JavaScript, JQuery, Google Places API, Sqoot API
- https://github.com/frogman91/Foupon

LIRI 2017

- A back end command line node app to return tweets, song information, or movie information
- App logs commands
- Node.js, NPM Packages: Request, Spotify, Twitter
- https://github.com/jheal006/liri-node-app

# Jonathan P. Healy

jonathan.p.healy@gmail.com | 858.395.4047

Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub

Bamazon 2017

- Backend command line interface which mimics a storefront application
- Node.js, NPM Packages: Request, MySql
- https://github.com/jheal006/bamazon

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Motivating the Masses San Diego, CA

06/2017 - Present

## Front End Developer

- Responsible for front end maintenance of <a href="www.motivatingthemasses.com">www.motivatingthemasses.com</a> including updates, bug fixes, content and advertisement insertions and deletions.
- Technologies utilized include HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Drupal, PHP, and SQL.

Sunset Motors, Inc. San Diego, CA

07/2013 - 05/2017

### **Operations Manager**

- In charge of day to day operations including customer service, long term reservation booking, and fleet maintenance of over 100 vehicles.
- Pricing and rate control across multiple brands

Drivetime, Inc.

Riverside, CA

07/2011 - 06/2013

#### Sales Associate/Underwriter

- Verified customer credit ratings, worthiness, and analyzed credit reports as a basis for loan options and terms.
- Customer service specialist and sales liaison between senior loan underwriters, management and the customer base

Sunset Motors, Inc.

San Diego, CA

02/2010 - 06/2011

#### Rental Agent

- Customer service liaison and in charge of rental operations.
- Established customer relations by advising clients on logistic planning for both moves and travel plans.